Hilmar Ragnarsson

Software Developer



Barcelona, Spain



hilmarragnars@gmail.com



hilmarragnars



linkedin.com/in/hilmarragnars

Hard Skills

Programming Languages

Python, C/C++, JavaScript SQL, Java C#, Prolog PHP, Ruby, SML, AL

Frameworks/Libraries

Django, React, Redux jQuery Node.js, Rails Flask, Angular

Other

CSS, HTML Git, Unix/Linux Systems **Styled Components** Agile, Scrum **Test Driven Development** Sublime Text, Atom Visual Studio, Xcode SeleniumHQ, Python Unittest

Unity. Ot **PCL Programming** MongoDB, MySQL

Soft Skills

Leadership Teamwork Networking Critical Thinking **Problem Solving** Self-motivation

Verbal and Written Communication

Adaptability

Time Management

Public Speaking

Creativity

Languages

Icelandic: Native English: Fluent Spanish: Fluent Intermediate Danish:

I am a highly motivated Software Developer with invaluable experience in various information technology sectors. Driven by the desire to push my creative limits, I want to be part of an ambitious and forward- looking organization where I can be engaged in innovative projects. I am an enthusiastic problem solver with passion for technology and exceptional interpersonal skills. My dream is to grow as a developer working on a project that I genuinely believe in.

Experience

Full Stack Web Developer 2017-07 -

2019-05

Broadsheet Media, Melbourne, Australia

- Intensive frontend development with React Redux
- Consistently improved the backend build with Diango
- Gained thorough experience with the Django REST framework
- Converted the whole SCSS to Styled Components, over 10.000 lines of code for more than 100 components
- Built a website on my own in Django for the commercial team

Python Diango Developer 2016-07 -

2017-07

Smartvel, Madrid, Spain

- Got to know Django in depth by creating an app for filtering and sorting data extracted from the web
- Contributed to the development of their web scraping engine
- Developed tests and set up a unit test framework for the front-end written in Angular

Teaching Assistant 2014-08 -

2015-06

Reykjavik University, Iceland

- Teaching assistant for students in C++ programming and Data Structure
- Evaluated the student's exams in C++ programming and Data Structure
- Administered several groups of students who were working on their final project in Qt and evaluated their work

Education

2013-08 -**BSc in Software Engineering**

2015-06

Reykjavik University, Iceland

- Graduated with the grade 9,1
- Reykjavik University Dean's list for exceptional academic achievement in the Department of Computer Science

Software Engineering 2015-08 -

2016-05

Universidad Carlos III, Madrid, Spain

- Finished the last year of my bachelor in Madrid as an exchange student
- Majority of the coursework was in Spanish

2012-08 -**Mathematical Engineering Department**

2012-12

Viterbo University, Wisconsin, USA

• Invited to attend on a soccer scholarship

Matriculation in Natural Science 2008-08 -

2012-05

The Commercial College of Iceland, Reykjavik, Iceland

• Upper secondary school/Junior College in Iceland